JANET YODER

7205 W. 21st. Street Greeley, CO 80634 kajcyoder@comcast.net

www.linkedin.com/in/janetyoder Cell: 970-396-9428

SUMMARY

Accomplished professional that is combining a strong software development background with Web development skills. Top strengths include: excellent interpersonal skills, utilizing teamwork to get results, and being detail-oriented without losing sight of the overall goal. Experience in:

- Designing, building, editing web sites
- Responsive design
- Knowledgeable in Adobe Suite
- Product/Project/Program Management
- Scrum Master and Agile practices
- Escalation Management and process creation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Visual Studio, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML/HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C++
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Microsoft Project, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Visio, SharePoint
- Subversion, GitHub, Sublime, Brackets, HP Quality Center/ALM, XPlanner, VMWare

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Front Range Community College Longmont, CO

WebLab - A Web Development Boot Camp, FRCC Certificate (2014)

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, UI/UX Design

Aims Community College Greeley, CO

Graphics Software and Applications Certificate (2014)

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign CS5 and CS6, Typography and Layout, Electronic Pre-press

Complete Web Authoring Class (2014)

HTML5 and CSS3 – Created a 5 page website for the final project.

University of Northern Colorado Greeley, CO

Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics, Emphasis: Computer Science

Corporate Sponsored and Personal Training

- Codecademy.com Completed JavaScript, jQuery, PHP class.
- Lynda.com WordPress Essential Training, Google Analytics Essential Training, JavaScript and AJAX, JavaScript and JSON
- Writing Windows 8 Metro Applications with XAML, Windows Store Data binding and MVVM
- Agile Estimating and Planning, Coaching Agile Teams, Demonstrating Responsibility: The Mindset of an Agile Leader, Designing the Agile, Organization Who Does What, Certified Scrum Master Training, Windows CE Development, Microsoft SharePoint 2010
- Project Management, Program Management, Project Leadership and Communication, TCP/IP Workshop, Managing Offshore Vendors
- Java, Fundamentals of XML, Programming with C#, Power ASP .NET Programming
- Prototyped with C# on writing Window 8 applications for the Windows Store. Owner of the submission of my team's HP Scan and Capture application to the Windows Store.

Janet Yoder Page 2

KEY PROJECTS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

To view the websites and source code go to: http://jcyoder.github.io/

Numerous Bootstrap Websites

Sites are live and the customer has access to changing the content, so sites may not look the same.

• http://www.drnuzum.com/

- http://www.coloradobizwomen.com
- http://www.theconnectingexperts.com
- http://www.stuffnmallows.com

The Kitchen Web Site

Site uses HTML5 and CSS3 to demonstrate the use of HTML and Google forms, an embedded Google map, AJAX calls, tables, iframes, @media for responsive design and some jQuery.

Todos Web Application

Demonstrates HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to allow to add, remove, edit, cross off, and filter todo list items.

Calculator and Colorado Travel

- The calculator uses HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript event handlers to create a basic calculator.
- Colorado Travel shows use of jQuery event handlers for submenu navigation and responsive design.

Adobe Suite Projects

2015 calendar, magazine layouts, 8 page booklet, email and coupon ads, photo collage, posters.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALLPROWEBTOOLS, Fort Collins, CO 2014 - 2016

Web Developer and Graphic Designer

Created numerous websites using Bootstrap 3, HTML5, CSS3 and the AllProWebTools framework. Gained experience in PHP, and MySQL. Created email ads, coupons, and other graphic design content. Creation of email templates for newsletters. Posting of syndicated blogs to medium.com, tumblr.com, linkedin.com, and blogger.com.

HEWLETT-PACKARD, Greeley/Fort Collins, CO 1993-2013

Sustained Engineering Lead for Windows Software (2013)

Led the team to create processes for managing customer issues and pre-sales opportunities for a \$182 million scanner software portfolio.

Scanner and Camera Product Engineer and Program Manager (1997-2013)

Managed the requirements, schedule and software solution life-cycle for HP's market leading scanners and HP Photosmart cameras.

Certified Scrum Master (2009-2012)

Led the team transition from a waterfall product life-cycle to using Agile. Managed the Scrum process to ensure the Scrum values, practices and rules were enacted and enforced.

Software Developer (1993-2003)

Developed code and maintained components shipped with HP Scanjet Scanner solutions, HP Photosmart Digital Cameras, HP Personal and Photo Printers and HP All-in-One devices.